<document>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>01</DOCNO>
<DATE>20171030
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
CNBC  30 OCTOBER 2017 / Tony Podesta reportedly leaving lobbying firm amid Mueller probe
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Tony Podesta, founder of the Podesta Group lobbying firm, is leaving the company after becoming a subject in Special Counsel Robert Mueller's investigation, Politico reports. NBC News reported last week that Podesta's company had worked on a public relations campaign that former Trump campaign chairman Paul Manafort had organized to improve Ukraine's image in the West. An indictment against Manafort and an aide on money laundering and tax evasion charges was unsealed Monday. Podesta, a Democratic lobbyist whose brother John was Hillary Clinton's presidential campaign chairman, announced his decision to step down during a company meeting on Monday morning, Politico reported. He will give full operational and financial controls to CEO Kimberley Fritts, according to Politico. Fritts and a senior group of people will launch a new firm within the coming days, Politico reported, noting that sources said the transition has been in the works for the past several months. Neither Tony Podesta nor The Podesta Group immediately responded to CNBC's requests for comment. Read Politico's full report here.
</TEXT>
<PUB>CNBC
</PUB>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>02</DOCNO>
<DATE>20160803
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
CNBC  03 AUGUST 2016 / President and Congress failing to fight Zika in Florida: Gov Rick Scott
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Washington is failing to adequately fund the fight against the mosquito-borne Zika virus even as the first cases of local transmission crop up in the Miami area, Florida Gov. Rick Scott said Wednesday "The president and and Congress have not worked together to help us," the Republican executive told CNBC's "Squawk Box." "Think about this, this is not just a Florida issue. This a national, international issue. We're just the tip of the spear. They should be our partner, and they haven't been our partner so far," he said. The White House and lawmakers have clashed this year over funding levels for Zika. President Barack Obama has requested $1.9 billion for mosquito control, vaccine research and other measures. A Republican-drafted plan to allocate $1.1 billion failed in the Senate this summer after Democrats objected to funding cuts to other health initiatives contained within the proposal, as well as a stipulation that would have blocked the money from being routed through private entities including Planned Parenthood. The threat became more urgent after the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention this week warned pregnant women to avoid the Wynwood neighborhood north of Miami, where the Florida Department of Health has identified 14 cases in which 
Zika was transmitted locally by a mosquito bite. A 15th case was reported Tuesday outside the one-square mile area where the virus has been transmitted. A health official told The Miami Herald the department is investigating whether active transmission is spreading beyond that area. The warning was the first of its kind in the United States. Until recently, cases of Zika virus, which the CDC has concluded causes microcephaly and other birth defects, have been limited among U.S. residents to people who traveled outside the Lower 48 states. In the absence of federal funding, Scott vowed to draw on state reserves and spend what was necessary to pay for ongoing efforts, including free Zika testing and spraying of insecticide. Scott confirmed that Obama offered to send $5.6 million to Florida while Congress is on recess, but said the president must work with lawmakers to reach a deal to offer more substantial funding. Rep. Ted Yoho, R-Fla., told "Squawk Box" that Republicans on Monday would formally request Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell to call Congress back to take up the issue. "We've asked Mitch McConnell to go ahead and bring this up and fast track it and get it done now. They should use the nuclear option of 51 votes and pass this without playing politics with it," he said. Rep. Debbie Dingell, D-Mich., told "Squawk Box" she would support reconvening Congress, but said the original Republican plan would cut funding for contraception that could prevent women who contract Zika through sexual intercourse from becoming pregnant. Dingell and her Democratic House colleagues voted against the Zika bill over funding concerns. They also opposed Republican efforts to relax EPA regulations on the use of certain pesticides that Democrats say could poison water sources. "Compromise is not a dirty word, and I'd like to see us come together because we have a crisis," Dingell said.
</TEXT>
<PUB>CNBC
</PUB>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>03</DOCNO>
<DATE>20190402
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
CNBC  02 APRIL 2019 / PRECIOUS-Gold steadies near four-week low as equities, dollar climb
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
* SPDR gold holdings posted biggest fall in a month on Monday * Dollar hovers near three-week highs * GRAPHIC-2019 asset returns: http://tmsnrt.rs/2jvdmXl (Updates prices, adds details and comments) April 2 (Reuters) - Gold prices steadied near their lowest in about four-weeks on Tuesday as robust economic data from the United States and China tempered concerns of a global slowdown, boosting the dollar and riskier assets. Spot gold was up 0.1 percent at $1,288.53 per ounce at 1007 GMT, having touched its lowest since March 7 at $1,284.76 earlier. U.S. gold futures fell about 0.2 percent to $1,292.30 an ounce. "Gold continues to struggle with the bullishness we are seeing across the other sectors ... Today, the primary driver is the continuous strength of the dollar," said Saxo Bank analyst Ole Hansen. "(Global slowdown) concerns are most certainly easing. It's too early to say they are gone but they have eased, and with that, also the need to have protection." World stocks hovered just under a six-month high, supported while the dollar index rose to a three-week high against a basket of rival currencies, making bullion expensive for holders of other currencies. Investors are also keeping a close watch on Sino-U.S. trade negotiations, set to resume later this week in Washington with a Chinese delegation led by Vice Premier Liu He. Indicating investor sentiment, holdings in the world's largest gold-backed exchange-traded fund, SPDR Gold Trust , fell 1.5 percent on Monday, their biggest one-day percentage decline in a month. The $1,275-80 level remains the key area 
of attention and break below that could signal a deeper correction, Saxo Bank's Hansen said. Meanwhile, British Prime Minister Theresa May will chair a five-hour cabinet meeting on Tuesday in an attempt to plot a course out of the Brexit maelstrom as she comes under pressure to either leave the European Union without a deal or call an election. "Though gold prices have struggled in lieu of competing influences, increasing signs of economic weakness will remain supportive towards haven appeal in 2019," Phillip Futures said in a note. Among other precious metals, spot palladium was down1.2 percent at $1,402.50 an ounce. Silver slipped 0.4percent to $15.04 per ounce, while platinum was up 0.2 percent to $848.95. (Reporting by Sumita Layek in Bengaluru; Editing by Mark Potter)
</TEXT>
<PUB>CNBC
</PUB>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>04</DOCNO>
<DATE>20160617
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
CNBC  17 JUNE 2016 / Stocks close lower; Dow posts worst week in a month
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
U.S. stocks closed lower Friday, with health care and tech stocks lagging, amid continued uncertainty ahead of next week's scheduled Brexit vote. The Dow Jones industrial average lost 1.07 percent for the week, its worst since the one ended May 13. The S&P 500 lost 1.19 percent for the week and the Nasdaq composite 
fell 1.92 percent for the week. "The market's down 1 percent (this week) so it isn't a good week, but there's a tension between event risk ... and profit trends that are starting to look a little better," said Jeremy Zirin, head CIO investment strategist at UBS Wealth Management Americas. The Dow closed about 59 points lower after briefly falling 130 points. Apple and Merck had the greatest negative impact. Health care closed 1.1 percent lower to lead S&P 500 decliners, followed by a 0.9 percent fall in information technology. Apple closed near session lows, off almost 2.3 percent after news intellectual property regulators in Beijing barred the tech company from selling models of the iPhone 6 and 6 Plus in the city, citing strong similarity to an existing Chinese phone. Apple said in a statement to CNBC it is appealing the ruling and that the phones are available for sale today in China. The iShares PHLX Semiconductor ETF (SOXX) closed 0.85 percent lower for its first six-day losing streak since the one ended early January. The Nasdaq composite and S&P 500 had their worst weeks since the one ended April 29. Telecommunications and utilities were the only gainers on the week. The Dow transports closed more than half a percent higher Friday but fell 2.25 percent for the week, ending in correction territory, or more than 10 percent below its 52-week intraday high. The Russell 2000 lost more than 1.5 percent for the week, its worst since early April. "I think there are a lot of distractions in the markets this week. Obviously a lot of focus on the (EU) referendum and 
interest around the very dovish sentiment expressed by the Federal Reserve," said David Kelly, chief global strategist at JP Morgan Funds. "I think that's got 
the market really confused here." The U.K. vote on whether to leave the European Union is scheduled for next Thursday. "The reality is markets regard Brexit as being a source of big uncertainty," Kelly said. "I have to say the implications for the global economy and financial markets are probably smaller than people 
think. ... It's important to recognize central banks and major governments are strongly in favor of Britain remaining in the EU." The Federal Reserve kept rates unchanged at its meeting this week and Fed Chair Janet Yellen said Brexit concerns were a factor in the decision. The latest central bank statement came after the weak May jobs report. In a significant shift in economic views, St. Louis Fed President James Bullard said low growth and a very low fed funds rate of just 63 basis points will likely remain in place through 2018, implying just one more hike until that time. In economic news, housing starts declined 0.3 percent in May, while building permits rose 0.7 percent. "This week's economic news was not all that bad but certainly it doesn't point to the economy exploding to the upside anytime soon," said Peter Cardillo, chief market economist at First Standard Financial. Friday also marked options expiration. The third Friday of every March, June, September, and December is quadruple "witching," the expiration of three related classes of options and futures contracts, along with individual stock futures options. Treasury yields were higher, with the higher around 0.69 percent, after hitting its lowest since mid-February on Thursday. The 10-year yield around 1.61 percent, after touching its lowest since August 2012 on Thursday. The U.S. dollar index was about 0.4 percent lower, with the euro around $1.128 and the yen near 104.2 yen versus the greenback. Sterling was higher against the dollar near $1.436. U.S. stocks came off lows Thursday and closed higher, as the British pound recovered losses against the U.S. dollar to trade higher. Gold also came off session highs. The move in sterling coincided with news Britain temporarily suspended campaigning on the Brexit vote after a Labour member of Parliament was shot and killed. The cause of the shooting was unclear, but there was speculation the act could encourage more voters to choose to remain in the EU. Britain's parliament will be recalled on Monday to allow lawmakers to pay tribute to the slain legislator, the leader of her party Jeremy Corbyn said Friday. He was speaking alongside Prime Minister David Cameron near the spot of the shooting. Parliament has not been sitting since Thursday, to allow lawmakers to campaign ahead of a referendum on EU membership on June 23. "My sense is there's more of a chance the U.K.'s going to stay. That might be a catalyst (for stocks to come off session lows)," said Mike Bailey, director of research and chair at FBB Capital Partners. "The only other major driver here today is oil. Oil's back in a big way," he said. Energy was the top performing sector on the day 
and down mildly for the week. U.S. crude oil futures snapped a six-day losing streak, settling up $1.77, or 3.83 percent, at $47.98 a barrel. WTI fell 2.2 percent for the week, its worst since early May. The weekly oil rig count rose for a third-straight week with a gain of nine, according to Baker Hughes. On Friday, the major European indexes were up nearly 1 percent or more. The Euro STOXX 600 Banks index outperformed, closing more than 4 percent higher for its best day 
in about two months. However, the index was down nearly 1.4 percent on the week for its first three-week losing streak since the one ended in early April. Asian stocks closed higher, with the Nikkei 225 up more than 1 percent and the Shanghai composite about 0.4 percent higher. The Nikkei 225 fell more than 6 percent for the week, its worst since the one ended February 12. The Shanghai composite had its second-straight weekly decline with a fall of 1.44 percent. Verizon was the top performer on the week, while American Express was the greatest laggard. The closed down 6.77 points, or 0.33 percent, at 2,071.22, with health care leading five sectors lower and energy the top advancer. Telecommunications was the best performer on the week, while health care was the worst. About three stocks advanced for every decliner on the New York Stock Exchange, with an exchange volume of nearly 2.1 billion and a composite volume of 4.7 billion in the close. High-frequency trading accounted for 49 percent of June's daily trading volume of about 6.75 billion shares, according to TABB Group. During the peak levels 
of high-frequency trading in 2009, about 61 percent of 9.8 billion of average daily shares traded were executed by high-frequency traders. Gold futures for August delivery settled down $3.60 at $1,294.80 an ounce, its first negative day in eight after hitting a nearly two-year high intraday Thursday. The precious metal gained nearly 1.5 percent for the week, its first three-week win streak since the one ended February 12. —Reuters contributed to this report.
</TEXT>
<PUB>CNBC
</PUB>
</DOC>



</document>