<document>
	<DOC>
		<DOCNO>01</DOCNO>
		<DATE>20190128
</DATE>
		<HEADLINE>
CNN  28 JANUARY 2019 / Apple sponsors its first-ever camp for women entrepreneurs
</HEADLINE>
		<BYLINE>
   By CNN Business
</BYLINE>
		<TEXT>
San Francisco (CNN)The makers of LactApp are giddy to be at Apple Park, the iPhone maker's massive California headquarters. Four of the team members behind the mobile app, which provides bilingual guidance to breastfeeding mothers, have made the pilgrimage to Cupertino from their Barcelona headquarters.  They made the trip for the kick-off of Apple's first-ever Entrepreneur Camp, a two-week event aimed at helping female-led businesses that have an iOS app. At a launch event on Sunday in an Apple cafeteria, their excitement was palpable. Co-founder Maria Berruezo joked with her colleagues that they should go without sleeping to 
maximize what they get out of their time at Apple. The entrepreneurs were given little to no information about what the next two weeks of the camp would look like. Apple said companies would receive assistance in several areas, including how to better market their apps and improve features. "We don't know much. We're staying very close, and we know we have to show up here early in the morning. We'll do whatever they say we have to do," said Enric Pallarés, CEO of LactApp. 
"There's no actual program. We don't have a schedule."  The blind excitement is indicative of how much the companies could benefit from a relationship with Apple. App developers have made more than $120 billion through Apple's app store since it launched in 2008. To be accepted to the camp, companies have to be female-founded, co-founded or led by women, and must have at least one woman developer. The companies also have to have a working app or a prototype. Apple provides travel assistance on a case-by-case basis. Apple didn't say how many companies applied for the program, but ten finalists were chosen for this first event. The plan is to hold the camp quarterly, with 20 companies in future groups. Like many Silicon Valley companies, Apple is investing in programs to encourage more 
women to pursue careers in technical fields. It's an issue the industry continues to struggle with.  According to the National Center for Women &amp; Information Technology, 57% of the professional occupations in the US workforce in 2017 were held by women but women only held 26% of the jobs in computing.  Apple's most recent diversity report shows a 5% increase in women employees from 2014 to 2017. However, as of 2017, only 23% of its global employees who work in tech were women. Overall, only 32% of Apple's employees are women. At Sunday's event, men were in the minority, and everyone was hoping to get a boost for their company.  
"Apple puts you on the map in a very different scale. We are already a pretty well-known app in Spanish-speaking countries, but having Apple support the app just shows that we're [going] in the right [direction]," said LactApp's Pallarés. "We won't let them down."  Berruezo, one of the app's two female co-founders, said the camp is a "huge opportunity" for their company. "Apple is looking at us and it's very encouraging," she said. "We have many ideas. ... We want to develop everything, and being here is a great opportunity for us because we're at least going to be able to release new features in our app, [and] help mothers much more than we do now." Esther Hare, senior director of worldwide developer marketing at Apple, said she's spoken with some companies that don't qualify because they don't have a woman on their development team. She says they've started considering more female applicants in the hope of being accepted down the line, which is the point of the entrepreneur camp: to create more opportunities for women in tech. Kim Azzarelli's company, Seneca Women, just launched an app that helps professional women connect with other women around the world, to get advice and information about key issues. It also has a marketplace that features women-owned businesses.  Azzarelli has already partnered with  Procter &amp; Gamble (PG) on the app, called Seneca Connect, which will offer a corporate version of the tool to its employees. Partnerships like that will then help fund the public version, she said. She's hopeful that other companies will see Apple's camp and feel pressure to create programs of their own to help women entrepreneurs. "I think it's really important that Apple's stepping up," Azzarelli said.
</TEXT>
		<PUB>
CNN
</PUB>
	</DOC>
	<DOC>
		<DOCNO>02</DOCNO>
		<DATE>20190113
</DATE>
		<HEADLINE>
CNN  13 JANUARY 2019/ Gun gets through TSA screening at Atlanta onto Delta flight to Japan
</HEADLINE>
		<BYLINE>
   By Eric Levenson
</BYLINE>
		<TEXT>
(CNN)A  woman who carried a firearm onto a flight from Atlanta to Tokyo's Narita International Airport on January 3 returned to the US the same day she arrived in Japan, according to the country's Transportation Ministry. On Monday, the United States Transportation Security Administration (TSA) disclosed that a passenger at Hartsfield-Jackson Atlanta International Airport passed through a TSA standard screening checkpoint with a firearm after standard procedures were not followed. Japan's Transportation Ministry said there are no penalties for Delta Air Lines or TSA, but it does deem TSA responsible and asked the organization 
to take preventative measures. The passenger had forgotten the firearm was in their carry-on luggage, the TSA said. The incident was not part of a test.  "TSA 
has determined standard procedures were not followed and a passenger did in fact pass through a standard screening TSA checkpoint with a firearm at Hartsfield-Jackson Atlanta International Airport on the morning of January 3," the release states. Delta Air Lines also issued a statement to CNN, saying that "upon the customer's disclosure, the airline reported the incident to the TSA." The security breach came two weeks into the government shutdown, during which TSA agents have been required to work but have not received paychecks. CNN first reported on January 4 -- a day after the breach -- that hundreds of TSA agents from at least four major airports had called in sick. However, the TSA dismissed suggestions the government shutdown contributed to the security lapse and said a normal amount of staffers were working that day. "The perception that this might have occurred as a result of the partial government shutdown would be false," TSA said. "The national unscheduled absence rate of TSA staff on Thursday, January 3, 2019, was 4.8% compared to 6.3% last year, Thursday, January 4, 2018. So in fact, the national call out rate was higher a year ago than this year on that date." The TSA noted that it will "hold those responsible appropriately accountable." 
TSA screeners have struggled to detect weapons even in the absence of a shutdown. In 2015, the acting administrator for the TSA was reassigned after a report found that airport screeners failed to detect explosives and weapons in nearly every test that an undercover team conducted at dozens of airports. About 51,000 
TSA agents are among the 800,000 government employees working without pay or on furlough during the shutdown. The Air Traffic Controllers Union, Aviation Safety Inspectors Union and various other groups and air travel experts have issued statements condemning the various consequences of the shutdown, but the TSA and 
aviation experts have said flying is still safe. "Security standards will NOT and have NOT been compromised," said Michael Bilello, TSA assistant administrator for public affairs, on Twitter. In an attempt to ease the financial pain caused by the government shutdown, the TSA announced Sunday that it would provide a day's pay for those who were on duty the day after the lapse in funding, and also award $500 bonuses for work during the holiday travel season. "While I realize this is not what you are owed for your hard work ... and what you deserve, I hope these actions alleviate some of the financial hardship many of you are facing," TSA Administrator David Pekoske wrote. CNN's Junko Okura in Tokyo contributed to the report.
</TEXT>
		<PUB>
CNN
</PUB>
	</DOC>
	<DOC>
		<DOCNO>03</DOCNO>
		<DATE>20190205
</DATE>
		<HEADLINE>
CNN  05 FEBRUARY 2019/ PA Court orders Jerry Sandusky to be resentenced, denies his request for retrial
</HEADLINE>
		<BYLINE>
   By Rob Frehse, CNN
</BYLINE>
		<TEXT>
(CNN)The Pennsylvania Superior Court on Tuesday ordered convicted child molester Jerry Sandusky to be resentenced, but denied his request for a new trial, according to court documents. The former Penn State assistant football coach was convicted in 2012 of sexually abusing 10 boys, spanning over at least 15 years, 
and was sentenced in a lower court to at least 30 years in prison. The Superior Court has now ruled it was illegal to impose mandatory minimum sentences during the sentencing and ordered the lower court to re-sentence Sandusky "without application of any unlawful mandatory minimum sentences." Attorney Al Lindsay, who now represents Sandusky, says he's hopeful that the lower court will reduce Sandusky's sentence, but there's no way to know if that's going to happen until the resentencing takes place. Read: Praise for victims, jurors after Sandusky verdict Lindsay told CNN he spoke to his client about today's decision. "He's disappointed, but we're in for the long haul with this, and Jerry understands that it's going to be a long fight," Lindsay said. Lindsay added that he will appeal Sandusky's case to the Pennsylvania Supreme Court next.
</TEXT>
		<PUB>
CNN
</PUB>
	</DOC>
	<DOC>
		<DOCNO>04</DOCNO>
		<DATE>20190204
</DATE>
		<HEADLINE>
CNN  04 FEBRUARY 2019/ Liam Neeson expresses regret for once contemplating racist revenge
</HEADLINE>
		<BYLINE>
   By Megan Thomas, CNN
</BYLINE>
		<TEXT>
(CNN)Liam Neeson has revealed that years ago he contemplated carrying out a racist revenge attack after someone close to him was raped. The actor shared the 
story Monday in The Independent during a press tour for his new movie, "Cold Pursuit." He expressed regret for his "horrible" past behavior. Neeson began recounting his personal story after being asked about his film character turning to anger. He did not reveal who was attacked but said he found out when he returned home from a trip. "She handled the situation of the rape in the most extraordinary way," Neeson told the newspaper, which published an audio excerpt. "But my 
immediate reaction was ... did she know who it was? No. What colour were they? She said it was a black person. "I went up and down areas with a cosh [crowbar], hoping I'd be approached by somebody. I'm ashamed to say that, and I did it for maybe a week -- hoping some [Neeson gestured air quotes with his fingers, according to the Independent] 'black bastard' would come out of a pub and have a go at me about something, you know? So that I could kill him." Neeson said it took him about a week to process what had happened. "It was horrible, horrible, when I think back, that I did that," he said. "And I've never admitted that, and I'm saying it to a journalist. God forbid." "Holy s***," said Tom Bateman, his co-star, who was reportedly sitting next to Neeson during the interview. "It's awful," Neeson continued. "But I did learn a lesson from it, when I eventually thought, 'What the f*** are you doing', you know?" CNN has not been able to independently authenticate the audio. A rep for Neeson has not responded to a request for comment. Neeson, 66, added that growing up around violence in Northern Ireland taught him that revenge ultimately doesn't work.   "I come from a society -- I grew up in Northern Ireland in the Troubles -- and, you know, I knew a couple of guys that died on hunger strike, and I had acquaintances who were very caught up in the Troubles, and I understand that need for revenge, but it just leads to more revenge, to more killing and more killing, and Northern Ireland's proof of that. All this stuff that's happening in the world, the violence, is proof 
of that, you know. But that primal need, I understand."
</TEXT>
		<PUB>
CNN
</PUB>
	</DOC>
</document>