<document>
	<DOC>
		<DOCNO>01</DOCNO>
		<DATE>20190702
</DATE>
		<HEADLINE>
REUTERS  02 JULY 2019 / Europeans urge Iran to abide by nuclear pact; Israel says preparing military
</HEADLINE>
		<BYLINE>
   By John Irish, Parisa Hafezi
</BYLINE>
		<TEXT>
PARIS/DUBAI (Reuters) - European signatories to a nuclear pact with Iran said on Tuesday they were “extremely concerned” by Tehran’s apparent breach of the 2015 deal, as Israel said it was preparing for possible involvement in any confrontation between Iran and the United States.       Iran announced this week it has amassed more low-enriched uranium than is permitted under the nuclear pact, a move that prompted U.S. President Donald Trump to say Iran was “playing with fire”.  “We regret this decision by Iran, which calls into question an essential instrument of nuclear non-proliferation,” the foreign ministers of Germany, France and Britain said in a joint statement with the EU’s High Representative on Iran. “We urge Iran to reverse this step and to refrain from further measures that undermine the nuclear deal,” they said.  Tensions between Washington and Tehran have increased since Trump pulled Washington out of the pact last year and moved to bar all international sales of Iranian oil. Washington also blames Iran for attacks on oil tankers in the Gulf, something Tehran denies.  The European signatories to the accord have sought to pull back the two longstanding foes from direct confrontation, fearing a mistake could lead to war accidentally.  Israel has encouraged the Trump administration to press ahead with sanctions against its arch-foe Iran, predicting that Tehran will eventually renegotiate a more limiting nuclear deal.  But Foreign Minister Israel Katz told an international security forum that Iran might accidentally stumble out of what he termed the “gray zone” of contained confrontation.  “It should be taken into account that mistaken calculations by the (Iranian) regime ... are liable to bring about a shift 
from the ‘gray zone’ to the ‘red zone’ - that is, a military conflagration,” he said in a speech to the Herzliya Conference.  “We must be prepared for this, and thus the State of Israel continues to devote itself to building up its military might for the event that it will have to respond to escalation scenarios.”  Israel has long threatened to take preemptive military action to deny Iran the means of making nuclear weapons. Tehran says it has no such designs. One of its senior lawmakers warned on Monday that Israel would be destroyed within “only half an hour” should the United States attack Iran.      Iranian Foreign Minister 
Mohammad Javad Zarif denies that Iran is in violation of the nuclear accord by amassing more low-enriched uranium, saying Iran is exercising its right to respond following the U.S. pullout.  By exceeding the limit, Tehran could prompt the return of all international sanctions on Iran but one European diplomat, asked 
if Europe would trigger a dispute resolution mechanism that is part of the accord, said:  “Not for now. We want to defuse the crisis.”  A second diplomat said 
Britain, France and Germany would focus on bringing Iran back into compliance and that they wanted to gain more time for dialogue.   “In the immediate term, Iran must return to its obligations. There is room for dialogue,” a French diplomatic source added.  China, like France a signatory to the deal, said it regretted Iran’s move but urged all parties to exercise restraint and said the U.S. policy of increasing pressure on Iran was the “root cause of the current tensions”.  The nuclear deal lifted most international sanctions against Iran in return for curbs on its nuclear work. It aimed to extend the time Tehran would need to produce a nuclear bomb, if it chose to, from roughly 2-3 months to a year.  Iran’s main demand - in talks with the European parties to the deal and as a precondition to any talks with the United States - is to be allowed to sell its oil at the levels before Washington pulled out of the deal and restored sanctions.   Iranian crude exports were around 300,000 barrels per day or less in late June, industry sources said, a fraction of the more than 2.5 million bpd Iran shipped 
in April 2018, the month before Trump withdrew from the nuclear deal.      Iran says it will breach the deal’s nuclear curbs one by one until it is able to sell that amount of oil, saying this is the least it should be able to expect from an accord that offered economic gains in exchange for nuclear restrictions.    
Iran’s semi-official Fars news agency reported on Monday that the Islamic Republic’s enriched uranium stockpile had passed the 300kg (661 lb) limit allowed under the deal.  “We have NOT violated the #JCPOA,” Zarif wrote on Twitter, referring to the deal by the abbreviation of its formal title, the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action.  Iran’s parliament speaker Ali Larijani accused Trump of trying to bully Tehran with his remark about playing with fire, and said such language would only made Iran stronger.  Zarif reacted with exasperation to a White House accusation that Tehran had long violated the terms of the deal.   “Seriously?” he said in a one-word message on Twitter, after White House press secretary Stephanie Grisham said in a statement that “there is little doubt that even before the deal’s existence, Iran was violating its terms.”   Her comment contrasted with CIA Director Gina Haspel’s testimony in January to the Senate Intelligence Committee that “at the moment, technically, they are in compliance.”  Additional reporting by Francois Murphy in Vienna, Writing by William Maclean and Alistair Bell; Editing by Jon Boyle and Grant McCool
</TEXT>
		<PUB>
Reuters
</PUB>
	</DOC>
	<DOC>
		<DOCNO>02</DOCNO>
		<DATE>20190702
</DATE>
		<HEADLINE>
REUTERS  02 JULY 2019 / Ireland faces backlash from farmers, opposition over Mercosur deal
</HEADLINE>
		<BYLINE>
   By Padraic Halpin
</BYLINE>
		<TEXT>
DUBLIN (Reuters) - A draft trade deal between the European Union and Mercosur bloc of South American countries has put Ireland’s government under intense pressure from farmers and opposition parties concerned over the
 impact on the country’s beef sector.  Mercosur struck its first major pact on Friday in its deal with the EU, but the potential boost to South American beef exporters angered Ireland’s large beef sector, which is already 
 under strain due to Brexit.  The Mercosur deal is also meeting resistance in the EU’s largest farming power, France.  The Irish Farmers’ Association said the deal will decimate the Irish beef market by allowing cheaper 
 South American cuts into the EU. The group’s national livestock chairman, farmer Angus Woods, said the effect was potentially even worse than Britain’s exit from the European Union.  Farmers’ concerns have dominated 
 newspaper frontpages and proceedings in parliament when it sat for the first time this week on Tuesday. The main opposition Fianna Fail said the deal signaled the “death knell” for the industry.  Irish Prime Minister Leo Varadkar said on 
Monday the government will conduct a full economic assessment of the impact the entire deal will have on Ireland, adding it would vote against it if the risks outweighed the benefits.  That followed an intervention from Agriculture Minister 
Michael Creed who said Dublin was not without allies on the issue, naming France, Belgium and Poland as countries Ireland had teamed up with previously to raise concerns.    “What you have is a Commission in its last hours agreeing a deal that
 no member state or national parliament has agreed. It is a bad deal, there is no point in saying otherwise, it’s a bad deal for the beef sector,” Creed told national broadcaster RTE.  As one of the smaller members of the 28-member bloc, Ireland would 
 need fellow member states to form a blocking minority if it sought to reject the deal, as ratification will eventually be put to a qualified majority vote.  While French President Emmanuel Macron said on Saturday the draft deal was “good” and had met key 
 French demands, his foreign minister said on Tuesday that it remained to be seen whether it met those demands.  For Ireland, the pressure from the powerful farming lobby comes after it quelled protests from beef producers by reaching a deal with the EU to 
 compensate them for the fall in prices suffered as a result of the Brexit process.  Editing by Frances Kerry
</TEXT>
		<PUB>
Reuters
</PUB>
	</DOC>
	<DOC>
		<DOCNO>03</DOCNO>
		<DATE>20180329
</DATE>
		<HEADLINE>
REUTERS  29 MARCH 2018 / Merits of any Takeda bid for Shire questioned, shares slide
</HEADLINE>
		<BYLINE>
   By Ritsuko Ando, Minami Funakoshi
</BYLINE>
		<TEXT>
TOKYO (Reuters) - A potential acquisition of London-listed Shire SHP.L by Takeda Pharmaceutical (4502.T) was greeted with investor scepticism about its merits on Thursday, with shares in the Japanese drug maker tumbling 7 percent.  Takeda, currently worth 
some $39 billion, is smaller than Shire, a rare disease specialist which saw its shares jump 16 percent to be valued at some $45 billion after the Japanese firm said it was in a “preliminary and exploratory stage” of considering a bid.  That similarity in 
size has raised the question of whether the damage to Takeda’s finances would be worth the boost to its portfolio and pipeline.   “The impression left by the news is that the acquisition would be an overreach,” said Mizuho Securities analyst Hiroshi Tanaka 
in a note to clients.  Any deal is expected to involve some form of equity, whether that be a share swap or a share issue, analysts also said, noting a share issue could be highly dilutive for Takeda shareholders.  Takeda said an acquisition of Shire, which 
also sells treatments for attention deficit disorder, could create a global biopharmaceutical leader, boost its position in the United States and in the fields of oncology, gastrointestinal diseases and neuroscience.  But some analysts also doubted whether Shire’s 
treatments for haemophilia and other rare diseases would benefit Takeda and thought that any deal should be more targeted.  “We think neuroscience assets alone, which Shire said are under strategic review, would be a realistic target, but we find it hard to imagine 
Takeda acquiring all of Shire,” said UBS analyst Atsushi Seki.   “We think the possibility of it making a proposal is very low, but its share price will likely be under pressure from concern over potential dilution.”  Takeda’s potential bid for Shire, most of whose 
employees are based in North America, immediately stoked expectations for another takeover battle in the deal-hungry pharma industry.  In recent months, France’s Sanofi (SASY.PA) agreed to buy U.S haemophilia specialist Bioverativ BIVV.O for 
$11.6 billion and Belgium’s Ablynx ABLX.BR for 3.9 billion euros ($4.8 billion). Before that, U.S.-based Celgene (CELG.O) bought cancer specialist Juno Therapeutics JUNO.O.   Japanese companies, faced with a rapidly shrinking population, are seen as particularly 
acquisitive. Takeda, founded in 1781 as a purveyor of traditional herbal medicine, has sought to internationalise through deals under its French CEO Christophe Weber, who took over in 2015.  (This story has been refiled to fix typographical error in first paragraph.)  
Reporting by Ritsuko Ando and Minami Funakoshi; Editing by Edwina Gibbs
</TEXT>
		<PUB>
Reuters
</PUB>
	</DOC>
	<DOC>
		<DOCNO>04</DOCNO>
		<DATE>20190625
</DATE>
		<HEADLINE>
REUTERS  25 JUNE 2019 / Akorn gets FDA warning letter for another manufacturing plant
</HEADLINE>
		<BYLINE>
   By Aakash B
</BYLINE>
		<TEXT>
(Reuters) - Akorn Inc said on Tuesday it received a warning letter from the U.S. Food and Drug Administration regarding its manufacturing facility in New Jersey, 
the latest in a string of setbacks for the generic drugmaker.  Shares of the company were down 1% at $4.67 in afternoon trading. They had fallen nearly 13% in trading 
before the opening bell on the news.  The FDA warning is the second that Akorn has received this year and follows an inspection of the company’s Somerset, 
New Jersey-based plant in July and August 2018.  In January, the agency issued a warning letter for Akorn’s other manufacturing plant in Decatur, Illinois after the 
drugmaker did not resolve previously highlighted violations such as failure to follow procedures to prevent contamination of drugs produced at the plant.  RBC Capital 
Markets analyst Randall Stanicky said the New Jersey plant is linked to less than 10% of products manufactured by Akorn, and the company’s primary focus would remain 
on moving past the warning letter it received for its Illinois facility.      The warning letter would likely require Akorn to carry out inspections, but should not 
impact production at the facility, Stanicky said in a note.  The FDA had also raised concerns about an Akorn manufacturing facility in Amityville, New York, earlier 
this year.  In addition to troubles at certain manufacturing plants, the company has seen the departure of its Chief Executive Officer Raj Rai, following its 
inability to salvage a $4 billion takeover deal with Germany’s Fresenius SE &amp; Co KGaA.  The company shares have fallen 70.5% over the past 12 months.    
Akorn on Tuesday said it will work to resolve all issues raised in the agency’s letter and that it expects to continue production at the Somerset facility.  
Reporting by Aakash Jagadeesh Babu in Bengaluru; Editing by Shailesh Kuber
</TEXT>
		<PUB>
Reuters
</PUB>
	</DOC>
</document>