<document>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>01</DOCNO>
<DATE>20160615 
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
NYT  15 JUNE 2016 / Review: Following ‘Figaro’ From Room to Room in a Townhouse
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By Anthony Tommasini
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
The valet Figaro bustles about, measuring the floor space of the new quarters he will soon occupy with Susanna, while, off to the side, she tries on a bridal 
hat. These are the beloved characters we know from Mozart’s “Le Nozze di Figaro.” But the unfamiliar music is by Marcos Portugal, born in Lisbon in 1762 and renowned in his time. On Tuesday night, the enterprising On Site Opera gave what it called the North American premiere of Portugal’s “The Marriage of Figaro,” also adapted from Beaumarchais’s incendiary French play. Portugal composed the work in 1799 for a Venice production (13 years after Mozart’s “Figaro” first played Vienna). This is the second installment of On Site’s presentation of unfamiliar operatic versions of Beaumarchais’s Figaro trilogy. It began last June with a charming production of Paisiello’s 1782 “The Barber of Seville.” That opera, so popular in its day, was later nudged aside by Rossini’s version. On Site Opera presents the ultimate in intimate productions by performing works in spaces that fit the setting of the story. The audience (inevitably small) follows the performers from room to room, along with a roving roster of instrumentalists. This delightful staging of Portugal’s “Figaro” takes place at 632 on Hudson, a beautifully renovated townhouse in the West Village, available for all manner of events. For this modern-dress staging by the imaginative director Eric Einhorn, the townhouse becomes Count Almaviva’s summer palace. The action begins in a large kitchen with long wooden tables. Chairs are set up for only some 50 audience members. (The run is sold out.) And talk about immersive opera — it’s quite dramatic when, say, the hearty baritone Jesse Blumberg, as Figaro, and the bright-voiced soprano Jeni Houser, as Susanna, exchange full-voiced phrases just inches away from you as they dash around that kitchen. When the opera shifts to the countess’s private chambers, the cast and audience move to a plush salon. The encounters in the garden take place in a bright atrium. On Site Opera’s music director, Geoffrey McDonald, working with José Luis Iglésias, has arranged the orchestra score for violin, cello, clarinet, oboe and, to provide some Iberian color, accordion, guitar and Portuguese guitar. Opera fans today, who know Mozart’s masterpiece, have to cut Portugal a little slack. The fetching, lyrically rich music, if lacking in depth and contrapuntal intricacy, abounds in vitality and wit. The opera (cut considerably) is performed here in a snappy English translation, with Portugal’s recitatives replaced with new spoken dialogue (by Joan Holden) based on Beaumarchais’s play. The wonderful cast includes the charismatic tenor David Blalock as the count, the plush-voiced soprano Camille Zamora as the countess, the formidable mezzo-soprano Margaret Lattimore as a take-charge Marcellina, and the soprano Melissa Wimbish in a show-stealing turn as the hormonal pageboy Cherubino. Ryan Kuster as Basilio, David Langan as Bartolo, and Antoine Hodge as Antonio were also excellent. Part 3 of On Site’s Figaro Project, presenting Milhaud’s “The Guilty Mother,” will be staged next year. The company has yet 
to figure out where.
</TEXT>
<PUB>NYT
</PUB>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>02</DOCNO>
<DATE>20160905
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
NYT  05 September 2016 / Opinion | Donald Trump’s Alt-Right Brain
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By The Editorial Board
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Editorial Donald Trump has devoted most of the past two weeks to discussing immigration, even though only 8 percent of Americans rank it as “the most important problem facing this country today,” according to a recent Gallup poll. But within that thin slice of the electorate reside Mr. Trump’s staunchest supporters, the “alternative right,” or alt-right. The Southern Poverty Law Center calls the alt-right “a set of far-right ideologies, groups and individuals whose core belief is that ‘white identity’ is under attack by multicultural forces using ‘political correctness’ and ‘social justice’ to undermine white people and ‘their’ civilization.” Most Americans hadn’t heard about the alt-right until this election, and some not until last month, when Hillary Clinton gave a speech in Reno, Nev., linking Donald Trump to it. The term was coined in 2008 by Richard Spencer, a white supremacist whose National Policy Institute says it is “dedicated to the heritage, identity and future of people of European descent in the United States, and around the world.” Through his online writings and YouTube channel, 
Mr. Spencer is a key player in the social-media universe where this core group of Trump supporters get their “news,” from sources with which most people aren’t familiar. A quick scan shows that immigration is not only their most important issue, it’s pretty much their only issue. “Immigration is a kind of proxy war — and maybe a last stand — for White Americans, who are undergoing a painful recognition that, unless dramatic action is taken, their grandchildren will live in a country that is alien and hostile,” Mr. Spencer wrote in a National Policy Institute column. Infowars is another website that puts immigration front and center. The site was created by the radio commentator/conspiracy theorist Alex Jones, who is the source of Mr. Trump’s false claim that thousands of New Jersey Muslims celebrated 9/11, and on whose show Mr. Trump said: “Your reputation is amazing. I will not let you down.” Infowars called Mr. Trump’s slashing anti-immigrant rant on Wednesday “an excellent speech sure to win him support from those who’ve been conned by the lying media into thinking he’s some evil demon creature when the truth is he’s a man with a heart of gold.” Mr. Trump says he isn’t signaling the alt-right when he says of immigrants, as he did again on Wednesday: “We have no idea who these people are, where they come from. I always say Trojan Horse. Watch what’s going to happen, folks. It’s not going to be pretty.” Or 
when he said — in a line widely quoted on alt-right websites — “There is only one core issue in the immigration debate and it is this: the well-being of the American people.” Mr. Trump’s white supremacist followers don’t take his disavowals too seriously. After all, he has enthusiastically retweeted bogus crime statistics and incendiary imagery from these websites and hired one of their biggest lights, Stephen Bannon of Breitbart News, to manage his campaign. There aren’t 
enough of these people to put Mr. Trump in the White House. But his candidacy has granted them the legitimacy they have craved for years. For the first time, a candidate is using a major-party megaphone to shout the ideas they once could only mutter among themselves in the shadowy fringes of national debate.
</TEXT>
<PUB>NYT
</PUB>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>03</DOCNO>
<DATE>20160509
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
NYT  09 MAY 2016 / Darren Criss to Return to ‘Hedwig and the Angry Inch’ for Opening of National Tour
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By Michael Paulson
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Darren Criss, the actor and singer best known for his role on “Glee,” will once again play the title role in “Hedwig and the Angry Inch,” this time on the West Coast. Mr. Criss played “Hedwig” on Broadway for three months last year. He will now open the show’s national tour, first in his hometown, San Francisco, at 
the SHN Golden Gate Theater, in October, and then in Los Angeles, at the Hollywood Pantages Theater, in November. The tour will then continue around the country; casting for other cities has not yet been announced. “Hedwig,” a rock musical about an East German singer whose sex-reassignment surgery went awry, features a book by John Cameron Mitchell and music and lyrics by Stephen Trask. The musical began its life with Off Off Broadway and Off Broadway runs, and then was adapted into a film, before making its way to Broadway in 2014; it won that year’s Tony award for best musical revival.
</TEXT>
<PUB>NYT
</PUB>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>04</DOCNO>
<DATE>20160728
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
NYT  28 JULY 2016 / U.S. Rebukes Israel Over New Settlement Activity in East Jerusalem
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By Diaa Hadid
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
JERUSALEM — The State Department sharply criticized Israel on Wednesday for taking steps to build hundreds of housing units in Jewish neighborhoods in East Jerusalem. The rebuke returned the settlement issue to the spotlight four weeks after the United States and other nations criticized Israel for continuing to build in occupied territory. John Kirby, the State Department spokesman, described the activities in a statement as “corrosive to the cause of peace.” “These steps by Israeli authorities are the latest examples of what appears to be a steady acceleration of settlement activity that is systematically undermining the prospects for a two-state solution,” Mr. Kirby said. The Israel Land Authority sought bids to build more than 300 units in a belt of territory around Jerusalem that Israel annexed after the Arab-Israeli war of 1967. Palestinians and many in the international community view the housing that Israel has built there as illegal settlements. Most Israelis see the area, where about 200,000 Jews now live, as regular suburbs. The contract tenders came after other announcements of building plans, including more than 500 housing units at Ma’ale Adumim, a Jewish settlement in the West Bank, and about 770 units in Gilo, a Jewish neighborhood built on annexed territory in southern Jerusalem. Those plans are not as advanced as the four tenders offers issued on Tuesday. The tenders, posted without fanfare on Tuesday on the land authority’s website, came to wide attention after they were publicized by Ir Amim, a group that monitors settlement activity in East Jerusalem. Three of the offers were reissues of earlier tenders that apparently attracted no suitable bids from construction companies. One was part of a 2012 plan, and others dated from a 2010 plan, said Michael Ben Aharon, a senior adviser to the mayor of Jerusalem, Nir Barkat. The neighborhoods affected are Gilo with 89 units, Har Homa with 130, Pisgat Ze’ev with 68 and Neve Yakov with 36. Pisgat Ze’ev and Neve Yakov are suburbs built between Arab neighborhoods. “As the 
recent Quartet Report highlighted, this is part of an ongoing process of land seizures, settlement expansion, legalizations of outposts, and denial of Palestinian development that risk entrenching a one-state reality of perpetual occupation and conflict,” Mr. Kirby said in the statement. “Quartet” refers to the United States, Russia, the European Union and the United Nations, which have been trying together to nudge Israelis and Palestinians to resume the peace negotiations that broke down more than two years ago. The quartet issued a report on July 1 calling on Israel to halt settlement construction and expansion, and to stop designating land for exclusive Israeli use. Nickolay E. Mladenov, the United Nations special coordinator for Middle East peace, said on Thursday that he was “increasingly concerned by the near-daily advancement of the illegal settlement enterprise in the occupied West Bank, including East Jerusalem.” But Mr. Ben Aharon said the new contract tenders were routine parts of a planning and building process that has been in operation for years. The Jerusalem municipality, he said, would “continue to develop all neighborhoods according to the city’s master plan, for the benefit of all of the city’s residents.” Israeli officials at the Foreign Ministry and prime minister’s office did not respond to requests for comment. A spokesman at the Israel Land Authority declined to comment. Further frustrating international officials, the tenders were issued at a time when Israel has stepped up demolition of Palestinian-owned buildings in East Jerusalem. Eleven houses, mostly vacant, were knocked down overnight in one village near Jerusalem on Tuesday, leaving piles of twisted metal and strewn rubble. The authorities said the structures were demolished because the owners had not obtained building permits. Palestinian residents and their supporters say the permits are extremely difficult to obtain. The United Nations Office of Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs said that by its count, 109 structures have been demolished in East Jerusalem this year, including 13 inhabited homes. The total for all of 2015 was 72 structures.
</TEXT>
<PUB>NYT
</PUB>
</DOC>



</document>