<document>
	<DOC>
		<DOCNO>01</DOCNO>
		<DATE>20170227
</DATE>
		<HEADLINE>
VICE  27 FEBRUARY 2017 / Now That We Can Alter Our Genetic Code, Should We?
</HEADLINE>
		<BYLINE>
   By Siddhartha Mukherjee, MD
</BYLINE>
		<TEXT>
A few days ago, I had just stepped off a podium at a cancer conference when a 50-year-old woman with a family history of breast cancer approached me. I had been discussing how my laboratory, among hundreds of other labs, was trying to understand how mutations in genes unleash the malignant behavior of cancer cells. 
She told me that she carried a mutation in the BRCA-1 gene—a mutation that she had likely inherited from her father.Diagnosed with cancer in one of her breasts when she was 30, she had undergone surgery, chemo, radiation and hormonal therapy. But that grim sequence of diagnosis and treatment, she told me, was hardly 
the main source of her torment. Now, she worried about the development of cancer in her remaining breast, or in her ovaries. She was considering a double mastectomy and the surgical removal of her ovaries. A woman carrying a BRCA-1 mutation has nearly a 60-70 percent chance of developing cancer in her breasts or ovaries during her lifetime, and yet it's difficult to predict when or where that cancer might occur. For such women, the future is often fundamentally changed by 
that knowledge, and yet it remains just as fundamentally uncertain; their lives and energies might be spent anticipating cancer and imagining survivorship—from an illness that they have not yet developed. A disturbing new word, with a distinctly Orwellian ring, has been coined to describe these women:  previvors—pre-survivors.Read more on Tonic
</TEXT>
		<PUB>
Vice
</PUB>
	</DOC>
	<DOC>
		<DOCNO>02</DOCNO>
		<DATE>20181211
</DATE>
		<HEADLINE>
VICE  11 DECEMBER 2018 / Google CEO Says No Plan to ‘Launch’  Censored Search Engine in China
</HEADLINE>
		<BYLINE>
   By Joseph Cox
</BYLINE>
		<TEXT>
On Tuesday, Google CEO Sundar Pichai testified in front of the House Judiciary Committee on a host of different subjects, including perceived political bias in the company’s search results, artificial intelligence, and alleged manipulation of search results. One looming issue though, which came up a handful of times in the hearing, is DragonFly, Google’s highly controversial search product for the Chinese market. As  The Intercept first revealed, DragonFly would censor certain search terms, in particular around human rights. The search platform would also make it easier for Chinese authorities to surveill and track those using 
the service.  During the hearing, Pichai responded to a question about DragonFly from US Representative Sheila Jackson Lee, who asked how the company could censor search results from users seeking a “lifeline” of democracy and freedom. “Right now we have no plans to launch in China,” Pichai said. Pressed again by US 
Representative Tom Marino on DragonFly, Pichai said “Right now there are no plans for us to launch a search product in China.” Marino asked how working with the Chinese government to help censor certain search topics can sit with Google’s core values. “We always have evidence, based on every country we have operated 
in, us reaching out and giving users more information has a very positive impact, and we feel that calling, but right now there are no plans to launch in China.”  Pichai said he will be fully transparent with policy makers if the company ever does “approach a position like that,” meaning launching a search product in China. Pichai described DragonFly as a "limited effort internally," and said the company developed "what search could look like" in China. According to  The Intercept, in July Ben Gomes, Google’s search engine chief, told staff that the plan was to launch the search product as soon as possible.  The Intercept noted 
the project has been in development since spring 2017, and involved around 300 employees. (Pichai said in one response that, at one point, the project had a hundred people working on it.) On Twitter, in response to Pichai’s comments, associate professor at the University of North Carolina Zeynep Tufekci wrote “this very answer must have been lawyered to death and practiced. The ‘launch’ is not planned for, yet. There are plans for search for China, just not plans for exactly how and when it gets launched.” Google did not immediately respond to a request for comment. After Pichai repeatedly claimed there are ‘no plans to launch’ 
its Chinese search engine, Marino asked what information the company would share with Chinese authorities if Google did offer a product in the country. “We would look at what the conditions are to operate,” Pichai said. It’s no secret that Chinese law is particularly strict against technology companies operating in the country, requiring them to hand over data collected on users. Apple outsources its Chinese iCloud services to a local company. An  Associated Press investigation recently found that shared data can even include information collected by cars such as Teslas. During the hearing, a protester held a poster at the doorway, showing a Google logo in the style of the Chinese flag, according to a tweet from CNN senior media reporter Oliver Darcy. “Getting access to information is an important human right,” Pichai said. Update: This piece has been updated to include additional comments from Pichai made during the hearing.   Subscribe to our new cybersecurity podcast, CYBER.
</TEXT>
		<PUB>
Vice
</PUB>
	</DOC>
	<DOC>
		<DOCNO>03</DOCNO>
		<DATE>20170511
</DATE>
		<HEADLINE>
VICE  11 MAY 2017 / Trump's Oddly Specific White House Eating Habits Have Been Revealed
</HEADLINE>
		<BYLINE>
   By Alex Swerdloff
</BYLINE>
		<TEXT>
 From ordering well-done steak slathered in ketchup, to de-crusting pizza and eating it with a knife and fork, to indulging in fast food because it is "clean," Donald Trump is known for his Howard Hughes-level picky opinions when it comes to food.  A gourmet, he is not. But his food choices do say something about the man. And now, for better or worse, we have yet another window into the existential-crisis-inducing clusterfuck that is our president's eating habits.  Reporters from TIME recently got a glimpse behind-the-scenes at the White House, where they reported on what goes down after business hours. Of particular interest—at least to us—was a meal enjoyed by the reporters, Trump, and Vice President Pence.  Pence's meal wasn't that weird—he ate what everyone else did, but was served fruit instead of pie for dessert; the VP is evidently watching his waistline. But the President received a meal fully customized to his own idiosyncratic (and not-too-healthy) preferences. The takeaway? The ruler of the free world gets to eat like the dad in a 1950s sitcom, his cholesterol count be damned. And, if 
everyone else is eating one serving of something—well, President Trump gets two. Here's the description that TIME offered of the Trump table:  "As [Trump] settles down, they bring him a Diet Coke, while the rest of us are served water, with the Vice President sitting at one end of the table. With the salad course, Trump is served what appears to be Thousand Island dressing instead of the creamy vinaigrette for his guests. When the chicken arrives, he is the only one given 
an extra dish of sauce. At the dessert course, he gets two scoops of vanilla ice cream with his chocolate cream pie, instead of the single scoop for everyone else." So now we know that Mar-a-Lago isn't the only place where Trump indulges his love of sweets. You'll recall, of course, that when describing how he told President Xi of China about the bombing of Syria, Trump got so caught up in the "beautiful" chocolate cake they were eating, he misspoke and claimed he had bombed Iraq. Two scoops of ice cream in addition to chocolate cream pie, after Thousand Island dressing and extra sauce? Guess it's good to be president. But maybe he should switch his Coke-summoning button in the Oval Office to diet.
</TEXT>
		<PUB>
Vice
</PUB>
	</DOC>
	<DOC>
		<DOCNO>04</DOCNO>
		<DATE>20170406
</DATE>
		<HEADLINE>
VICE  06 APRIL 2017 / Political Analyst Angela Rye Discusses Her Heated Showdown with Joe Walsh
</HEADLINE>
		<BYLINE>
   By Sarah Bellman
</BYLINE>
		<TEXT>
Angela Rye is not afraid to share her opinions. In a recent CNN segment, the political analyst did not hold back when criticizing former congressman Joe Walsh, who recently said that Obama was held to a "lower standard" as president because he's black.  When she visited VICELAND's  Desus &amp; Mero, Rye explained why she was so frank about Walsh's controversial statements and beliefs, and aired a few of her frustrations with the current political climate.   "I just think he shouldn't have been on TV," she told the VICELAND hosts. "Some people just don't deserve airtime. If people are bigots, you shouldn't help them be bigots." On a less political note, Rye also talked passionately about who she loves (and hates) on Love &amp; Hip Hop and whether or not sweet grits should exist. Check out the clip below. You can watch last night's  Desus &amp; Mero for free online now, and be sure to catch new episodes weeknights at 11 PM on VICELAND.
</TEXT>
		<PUB>
Vice
</PUB>
	</DOC>
</document>