<document>
<DOC>
<DOCNO>7679</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-CEPANADUFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>920516
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  16 MAY 92 / The guru who gives babies a human voice / Interview with
Penelope Leach
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By LUCY KELLAWAY
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
LAST Thursday was a big day for Penelope Leach. The woman who has encouraged
millions of parents around the world to treat their babies and toddlers as
free-thinking young human beings had just scored a triumph. The Scottish Law
Commission recommended that the slipper, the belt and the ruler should be
outlawed as intruments of punishment for children - a ban for which Leach
has been compaigning for years. 'I'm being rung for comments all the time,'
she says, inhaling deeply on a cigarette and running downstairs to the pine
kitchen in her north London house for another cup of coffee.
Throughout our conversation the phone keeps ringing, and not just about
smacking. Leach is being invited to write articles and asked for views on
child modelling, day care centres and other assorted themes. Indeed, she
has become a rent-a-quote expert. But she sticks to her liberal principles.
She is AGAINST smacking, regimentation, bottle feeding and communal child
care. She is FOR demand feeding, democracy within the family, and attending
to a baby as soon as it cries.
What makes her feel so strongly about it all? Did she herself have a
desperately strict upbringing that she is rebelling against?
'I'm afraid you are on a bad wicket there,' she says. 'We were a very close,
extended family. We were part of an arty tradition. My mother was a writer,
my stepfather was a painter and sculptor. We were never smacked - my mother
believed it was important that children should be allowed to argue, reason
their case, be heard.'
It was revolutionary stuff in those days. Dr Spock, Leach's forerunner and
inspiration, was still unknown in England. Baby and Child Care, which dared
to question the strict rules by which post-war children were brought up, was
not even published in Britain until 1955. Four decades later, it is almost
impossible to find an expert who is not in broad agreement with some variant
of the liberal ideas Spock introduced. And Leach, with her smash-hit book
Baby and Child - which has sold 2.5m copies in the US alone and has been
translated into 28 languages - is one of the loudest voices in the new
orthodoxy.
But isn't it odd that there seems to be a consensus on such an unscientific
business as bringing up children? Are the child-care experts so slavishly
fashion-conscious that they follow the liberal school for now, ready to
change everything should the mood swing back to discipline and routine? Or
is it that the liberals are, somehow, right?
Leach laughs and, after a bit of thought, plumps for the latter explanation.
'People have just recognised something that has always been perfectly
obvious. Children are people and it is more sensible to treat them as
people. It is better for everyone if you do.'
Her trademark is to write explicitly from the baby's point of view which,
she argues, is the same as the parent's. Surely, though, this is nonsense. A
two-year-old's interest is to throw toys all round the floor, but the
exhausted parent's is to get them cleared up as soon as possible and get the
child off to bed.
'Of course, the interests are not the same in that sense,' Leach replies.
'But what I passionately believe to be true is that getting it right for the
child is to get it right for the adult. You, as a parent, need the room to
be cleared up but you can't - you physically can't - force your child to
pick up the toys. If you want them up, well, look at it from her point of
view. By making it part of a game, or part of a race, you can get it done
and everyone will be happy.'
I look unconvinced. Might it not be quicker and easier just to exert your
will and put up with the screams?
'The issue here is power,' she says. 'Parents who say: 'What matters is my
power, my authority over the child' ' - she looks disapproving and takes
another long puff on her cigarette - 'those parents do not want my book.'
But even if you accept that parents should not be on a power kick - which
scarcely seems controversial - surely it is still unrealistic to expect
weary mothers and fathers to come up with a fun game at the end of the day.
Leach looks out onto her sunny garden backing onto Hampstead Heath, quite
unruffled.
Confident in her own ideas, she treats dissent with tolerance, almost with
sympathy. 'If people disagree with something I have written, then that at
least makes them think and helps them work it out in their own minds.
'When people complain that I have too idealistic a view of parents and
children, I say you have to aim high. We teach people to drive well, and to
observe speed limits, but that doesn't mean we always obey them. I am not
saying we can all do it right, but you have to aim high.'
I am still worried. I wonder if aiming high is responsible for all those
loving parents who bring their children to dinner parties and proceed to
keep them up throughout the meal, and those anarchic households where
toddlers rule the roost. Hasn't there been too much of democratic tolerance
and seeing the child's point of view?
Leach takes no responsibility for such behaviour. 'Children need adults, and
being an adult is about setting limits. People are extraordinarily bad at
setting limits.'
But how do you police the limits once you have set them - especially if,
going by her book, you are not allowed to punish and must avoid conflict?
'If you've set good limits, you don't have to police them,' she insists. 'A
good limit is one the child can't break.'
I wonder if someone with these views has children of her own, or has been
blessed with such good ones that conflicts never arose. This is another poor
wicket. Leach shudders. 'My daughter, in particular, was a difficult
toddler. Very difficult indeed. She was highly strung, very bright,
strong-willed, and understood an awful lot more than she could do.'
Didn't this experience of a difficult child make her question the views she
had formed, both as an academic and then while carrying out practical
research with thousands of parents?
'You don't believe things if the data contradicts them - at least, not if
you are any good. I had written about the validity of avoiding
confrontation; and when I got myself into a confrontation situation with my
daughter, it simply proved to me that this disastrous scene could have been
averted if I had seen it coming and taken another route.'
But what about ordinary mums? Does their experience also tally so well with
the Leach doctrine? Or are they leaving children to cry behind closed doors
knowing they will fall asleep eventually?
Leach, who speaks and writes with evangelical fervour, sighs. 'I come across
too many people who do not realise that very young children have feelings,
and that they matter. People still say of a three-year-old, in complete
amazement: 'She knows what she thinks]' On a good day, they think it is
quite sweet if a toddler has its own point of view; otherwise, they think it
extremely disrespectful'.
Leach feels, however, that most people have accepted the theory of modern
child-care - even if they do not actually put it into practice. 'Take breast
feeding,' she says. 'All the evidence we have is that breast feeding is
better for the child. Yet, fewer and fewer mothers breast feed in hospital
and an infinitesimal number go on until the baby is six weeks old. This
raises a difficult dilemma. If you, as an expert, believe differently from
common practice, then by stating your views you risk making a lot of people
very cross. If people don't want to breast feed, that is fine. But they must
accept that books should not blur the decision just to make them feel
better. Parents do not want to be lied to.'
Such intransigence has got Leach into trouble. Her opposition to communal
care for very young children has gone down badly with some working mothers.
'The media tends to leap to the conclusion that I am against women working,
but that is not true.' She adds, however: 'We need to recognise that work is
not everything. Our caring roles are just as important as our working ones.
We must de-genderise home-based roles. If women take equal responsibility in
the market place, men must do the same at home.'
It is easy to argue that this predictable stuff is distant from present-day
realities. But Leach, who still clings to a belief in flower power and
peace, might say justly that this is the reason it needs to be said - again
and again and again.
</TEXT>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page XXIV
</PAGE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO>8791</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-CELA7AATFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>920512
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  12 MAY 92 / Survey of Business in the Community (1): Partnerships that
work - Over the past 10 years many large UK companies and their employees
have entered into a wide range of activities in partnership with their local
communities.  The aim now is to encourage many more smaller businesses to
begin to participate
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By RICHARD EVANS
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
AROUND 100 senior business leaders meet in Birmingham and Newcastle today to
hear how they and their companies can get involved in helping the community
and at the same time help themselves.
The meetings are part of a campaign organised by Business in the Community
to extend and deepen the participation of companies in a range of local
activities and to ensure that community involvement becomes a natural part
of successful business practice.
They coincide with the 10th anniversary of BITC, an umbrella organisation
which helps create partnerships between business, government and local
communities to improve the economic, physical and social environment.
The organisation is at something of a crossroads, and is seeking to develop
a blueprint for expanding community involvement to virtually every company
in the country, not out of a sense of charity but out of enlightened
self-interest.
Mr Neil Shaw, chairman of Tate &amp; Lyle and the current chairman of BITC,
says: 'We need to move to Stage Two of our existence by significantly
enlarging our army of volunteers ...by doing so we develop better people and
as a result better companies.'
Today's conferences, spearheaded in Birmingham by Mr Robert Evans, chairman
of British Gas, and in Newcastle by Mr Iain Vallance, chairman of BT, are
part of a series of six across the country which follow an assessment of
BITC strategy last year called Directions for the Nineties.
Since the organisation was set up a decade ago, around 500 companies have
joined and several thousand have entered into local partnerships. The
question now is how these activities can best be expanded and developed by
involving more companies and more employees, and by linking community help
with other business functions.
Corporate community involvement in the UK can trace its roots back to the
Victorian era when industrialists such as Cadbury, Rowntree and Boot
provided free education for employees. Social 'investments' were viewed as
essential to commercial success, and they remain an essential ingredient of
family-led businesses such as Marks &amp; Spencer and J. Sainsbury.
However, under the Labour post-war administration, the central government
took more responsibility for social welfare, and corporate patronage
declined. It re-emerged in the late 1970s and early 1980s with the decline
of traditional manufacturing industries and increasing levels of social
alienation, particularly among the young and ethnic minorities.
Enlightened businesses began taking direct corporate action to rebuild the
health and vitality of local communities, and companies such as IBM (UK),
BP, Shell, British Steel, Barclays and Midland banks all developed community
involvement policies.
An Anglo-American conference at Sunningdale in 1980 led to the establishment
of a working party chaired by Sir Alastair Pilkington, chosen because of the
glassmakers' pioneering work with the St Helens enterprise agency, and this
committee laid the foundations for the launch of BITC in 1982. The profile
of the organisation was raised greatly in 1985 when the Prince of Wales
became president.
It was also the riots of 1981 in Brixton, south London and Toxteth,
Liverpool that gave the movement a big fillip. Mr Michael Heseltine, then
environment secretary, dragooned a group of senior businessmen on to buses
to show the devastation of Toxteth, and this proved to be the catalyst for
much wider action.
From its launch BITC supported the local enterprise agency movement as a job
creation vehicle for redundant employees and unemployed school leavers, and
the development of employment opportunities has remained an important
priority.
The private sector's work with LEAs and other community initiatives has
drawn thousands of large, medium and small companies into community
involvement. It has also developed the practice of partnership between the
private sector, local authorities, voluntary organisations and central
government, and paved the way for the establishment of Training and
Enterprise Councils (Tecs).
BITC, acting as an umbrella organisation and a disseminator of best
practice, has evolved into a national organisation with 11 regional offices.
Target teams focus on national issues, business leadership teams implement
programmes locally, and neighbourhood economic development partnerships
address urban regeneration problems at local level.
The Per Cent Club, administered by BITC, is a group of companies which have
agreed to contribute a  1/2 per cent or more of pre-tax profits, or 1 per
cent of dividends, to community based projects. Contributions take the form
of cash, staff secondments, or donations in kind such as equipment,
premises, time or expertise. More than 500 organisations are now members of
the clubs.
A Professional Firms Group pledges professional services free of charge to
community projects, including engineering, legal, accountancy, quantity
surveying and architectural services.
In the early years, help from business was concentrated on straight
charitable giving and sponsorship of the arts and sport. These are still
important but they now form a much smaller part of the total.
The issues facing the movement have become much more focused since
Directions for the Nineties was published after a lengthy consultation
exercise. They are the need to widen the range of support given by business
to the community, the need to include more employees in community
involvement, and the need to integrate community work fully into every
aspect of corporate life.
Mr Shaw, like other BITC leaders, stresses that a company's involvement in
the community must not be seen as just a charitable act, but as a 'two-way
street' that benefits the company as much as the community by generating a
more prosperous local economy.
He also emphasises the benefits to the individual of community work. 'I
would pay more attention to a successful involvement in a local project than
I would to success at business school,' he says.
Sir Allen Shepherd, chairman and group chief executive of Grand Metropolitan
and a deputy chairman of BITC, says: 'Corporate responsibility is not a
fringe activity. It is becoming an integral part of doing business.'
The GrandMet Trust has become the largest private agency in the country for
providing government-sponsored training and counselling programmes for the
unemployed. On any given day, 5,000 people will be attending a course, and
80 per cent of those completing one go on to find full-time employment.
The secondment of employees, favoured particularly by companies such as
Marks &amp; Spencer which donates Pounds 5.5m a year to community work, IBM,
banks and the big accountancy firms, has always been an effective link with
local communities.
The enterprise agency or local organisation gains from the secondee's
expertise and fresh approach to problems, and the company sees key employees
increase the range of their experience.
Kingfisher, which owns B &amp; Q, Comet and Woolworths, was a founder member of
the Opportunity 2000 campaign aimed at increasing the quality and quantity
of women's participation in the workforce, and the company has sponsored a
guide to corporate responsibility.
WH Smith is one of many companies that has encouraged employee participation
by matching pound for pound any sums raised. One recent exercise has been to
update the Samaritans' overloaded crisis phone lines.
Mr Sam Whitbread, chairman of Whitbread the brewers and chairman of BITC's
target team on employee volunteering, believes this area is the key to a
company benefiting from community activities. 'It can be used as a vehicle
for team building and staff development, it fosters positive communication
with otherwise disparate departments and generates a caring, service-driven
culture which can only lead to a commercial advantage,' he says.
The recession of the last 18 months has clearly had an impact on the
community involvement of some businesses. Redundancies and closures do not
sit happily alongside well publicised community projects. But the effect has
not been as great as might have been expected.
Mrs Julia Cleverdon, BITC chief executive, believes that support has been
well maintained partly because of the interest of chairmen and chief
executives who insist on a commitment being kept. It is also partly because
of a growing appreciation that the backing and sympathy of the local
community is particularly valuable to a company in difficult times.
What seems to have happened in recent years is that an increasing number of
large companies have appreciated the benefits of community involvement. But
this has not filtered down sufficiently to smaller companies, who wonder
whether they have the resources to act effectively enough.
What stops many business leaders from becoming involved in the community is
not unwillingness, but a lack of knowledge of the working mechanisms through
which their energies can best be channelled.
That is the purpose of today's meetings and of others to follow.
</TEXT>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 31I
</PAGE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO>9205</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-CEHA7AEYFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>920508
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  08 MAY 92 / Building site safety hangs by a thread: Diane Summers on an
initiative to reduce accidents in construction
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By DIANE SUMMERS
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
AN EVIL-looking hook is dangling from a piece of frayed rope. The
contraption is supporting a plastic dustbin full of building materials which
is being hauled by workmen up and down the outside of a three-storey
building in north London.
A short distance down the road, Mr Tim Small, Her Majesty's Inspector of
Factories, is observing the scene from his car. 'This is a fairly typical
set-up,' he says. 'It's cheaper to use old dustbins but they're not designed
to be loaded like that. The work is close to the pavement - if the dustbin
gives way, a member of the public could be seriously injured. We'd better
take a look.'
The work in progress is a re-roofing job, involving the addition of an extra
storey to the building. Such work is among the most dangerous: one in five
of all deaths in construction occurs during roof work. About three workers a
month are killed falling off roofs and numerous passers-by are hit,
sometimes fatally, by falling materials. Those figures are for the UK alone.
Europe-wide, construction provides just 8 per cent of total employment but
accounts for 16 per cent of serious accidents. Fatal accidents in
construction occur at three to five times the rate of industry generally.
EC directives aimed at tightening up site safety are on the way and this
year has been declared the year of safety, hygiene and health protection at
work by the European Commission. As part of the initiative, the Health and
Safety Executive is 'blitzing' building sites involving roof work in an
inspection campaign across the country. The campaign will not mean any more
inspectors on the streets, but Mr Small and his colleagues will be
concentrating their efforts on roofs during the next four months, the
busiest period in the roof work industry.
Outside the north London building, closer examination of the hook supporting
the dustbin shows it to be an improvised job, fashioned out of a bent
reinforcing rod. 'We'll have to put a stop to them using that straight
away,' says Mr Small, leaping up a couple of ladders and some scaffolding in
search of the workmen.
At the top of the building he looks down for evidence of 'bombing'  - debris
thrown into the garden. This practice is strictly verboten, says Mr Small,
except on sealed-off demolition sites. Thankfully, no bombing seems to have
taken place.
Back at ground level, a labourer grumbles that it is not his day: 'First the
van's wheelclamped, now you lot. I've never even seen a factory inspector
before.' Yes, they would have preferred to have used a proper chute instead
of the dustbin, but the boss didn't want to spend the money and they were
cutting corners all round on this job. No, they didn't have any hard hats
but, as it happened, the boss would be around with some later.
The boss arrives (no hard hats) to find out what is going on. Mr Small
delivers a lecture on the dangers of improvised hoisting gear. He is told of
a fatal case involving a falling bucket of boiling bitumen and a member of
the public. A legal notice is served forbidding the further use of the
dustbin-and-hook arrangement. The boss's attention is caught by the phrase
'fine of up to Pounds 20,000' if the legal notice is ignored.
Mr Small promises to send a safety information pack. 'I don't expect he'll
read it, but if there's an accident in future at least it'll be on file that
he's had it. If there's a prosecution, we could bring that to the court's
attention.'
It is the sixth time in the week that he has served a legal notice at a
construction site. He says it is good to keep the batting average up  -
everyone is impressed if you can point to an increased number of notices
served and more prosecutions than in the previous year. But he has
reservations about the time consumed in bringing cases to court and the
paltry fines that often follow.
'It's not always the best use of time,' he says. 'There might be a Pounds
150 fine for not wearing a hard hat and the magistrate asks why you're
picking on the guy. When you're in the office preparing paperwork for a
case, you're not out there where you should be, stopping the things that are
dangerous.'
</TEXT>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 9
</PAGE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO>9239</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-CEHA7AD0FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>920508
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  08 MAY 92 / EC threatens UK over border checks
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By DAVID BUCHAN
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   BRUSSELS
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
THE European Commission is threatening Britain with legal action if the UK
does not remove border checks on travellers entering from other Community
states by next January.
The threat is contained in the Commission's latest report on the state of
progress towards abolition of all controls on goods, services, capital and
people crossing internal EC frontiers.
The EC executive says, in its report issued this week, that it is
'resolutely determined to use all the legal and political means at its
disposal' to ensure fulfilment of Article 8a of the 1986 Single European Act
(SEA), which defines the internal market as 'an area without internal
frontiers'.
The Commission's maximalist interpretation of Article 8a has been known for
some time, and its threat of legal action is by no means solely directed at
the UK. Eight of the Community's continental members have already committed
themselves to a free travel zone, through the 1990 Schengen Convention, and
Greece has associated itself to the Schengen group as an observer. But
Denmark and Ireland are also dragging their feet on plans to abolish border
checks on intra-EC travellers - the former because of its passport union
with Nordic countries, and the latter because of its passport union with the
UK.
Nonetheless, the chief target of the report - which the Commission delayed
publishing during the recent UK election campaign - is Britain.
The UK has always argued that the SEA's commitment to free movement of
people applies only to EC citizens, and that controlling non-EC citizens
coming into the UK inevitably requires checking the credentials of EC
passport holders too.
In addition, the UK government argues that the SEA's commitment to free
movement is qualified by the treaty's explicit permission for member states
to take action against crime, drugs and terrorism. 'Many other EC states
agree that we need to keep controls' for these purposes, a senior UK
official said yesterday.
Increasing pressure from the Commission may embarrass the UK during its
presidency of the EC Council. If the Commission takes the UK before the
European Court it appears confident of winning.
</TEXT>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 3
</PAGE>
</DOC>
</document>